Bruno Batista do Nascimento Santos

São Paulo - Brazil

Cell phone: +55 11 959716775

E-mail: brunno1808@hotmail.com

Webpage: https://bbnsdevelop.github.io/brunobatista.github.io/

About me:

I have nearly ten years of experience in system development, and I am proactive, self-taught, evaluator, critical thinker, and planner. Throughout all phases of system development, I used design patterns and agile methodologies to ensure the best possible project completion. I enjoy assisting businesses in identifying technical and/or administrative solutions. I love teamwork and helping new developers learn about technologies.

I followed the evolution of monolithic architectures for microservices, agile development, and now DevOps methodologies during this time.CI/CD, Docker, Kubernetes, GitLab, Jenkins, Cloud Computing, and much, much more.

I love to communicate with my colleagues and share my knowledge. Absolutely, it is a critical step for the team to achieve success. I manage my time and tasks meticulously; by the way, I believe that organization is the key to everyone's success. I am also certified in Scrum Foundations Professional Certificate (SFPC). I enjoy putting an agile process into action because it allows me to develop and deliver with greater quality.

Technical skill:

Backend:

- Java 8, JUNIT
- Spring boot, Sprint data, Spring-Bacth, Spring Cloud, Spring security, JPA, Hibernate.
- Architecture of Microservices, Docker, Kubernets, AWS.
- Databases Oracle SQL, MySql, H2, PostgreSql and MongoDB.
- A litlle Python and NodeJs.

Frontend:

- Angular 2+.
- JavaScript, Jquery, Json, TypeScript, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap.

Others

- Jira, Agile methodologies: SCRUM, Kanban.

Academic education:

- Bachelor of Computer Science Nove de Julho University.
- Postgraduate Ethical hacking and Cyber security
- Quality Management Flamingo College.

Professional experience

Fullstack developer Java/Angular Senior at Stefanini - August 2018 - Present

Analysis of business requirements and preparation of technical projects for loan systems Development of new functionality for existing borrowing systems, including code writing, testing, and debugging Integration of loan systems with other banking platforms and backend systems Leadership of software development teams in loan projects participation in meetings with product managers and other stakeholders to discuss project progress and make important decisions. training and mentoring for newer programmers on the team. Maintenance and support of loan systems in production require constant research and learning of new technologies and tools related to loan systems.

This project are using tecnologys as:

Architecture microservices with Java 8; Docker; Nginx; Spring data, JDBCTemplate, Spring-Boot, Spring Cloud, Spring Security, api gateway zuul, Eureka service and client, Postaman; Unitary tests with Junit; Oracle SQL 11;

Code versioning GITLab; Code review; PullRequest; Json;, API Rest and Restful, Maven; Jira; Angular 2 more; HTML5, Bootstrap and Css styler.

Important to me in this Project. I had the opportunity to change of version angular 2 to version 8. Applying the best practices to update system:

Load Balance of modules, Angular Router using route guards,, Interceptor request Http.

Software engineer java mid at Codelt Solutions - of 2018 until 2018.

Analytics and development system with agile method. This project are using tecnologys as: Architecture microservices with Java 8; Docker; Spring data, JDBCTemplate, Spring-Boot, Spring Cloud, Spring Security, api gateway zuul, Eureka service and client, Postaman; Unitary tests with Junit; Oracle SQL 11:

Code versioning GITLab; Code review; PullRequest; Json;, API Rest and Restful, Maven; Jira; Angular 4; HTML5, Bootstrap and Css styler.

Software engineer java mid at Banck Santander - of 2017 until 2018

Development and Analysis of APIs for the banking sector using technologies: Java 7 and8; Hibernate, JPA, Spring Boot, Spring-Bacth, Spring Cloud, Apache TomCat 6, Apache TomCat 7, Apache TomCat 8, Oracle SQL, GIT, JSON, SOAPUI, REST, MAVEN, Micro applications, Micro Services, Integrations with external systems, Agile methodologies: SCRUM.

Analyst / Developer java fullStack jr At Stefanini - of 2016 until 2017.

Customer: Bank Original

Requirements gathering, understanding demands, maintenance, development and Analysis of banking systems interfaces in JSP, html5, JSF, Java-Script, Jquery, Ajax, Angularjs, Java 7; Hibernate, JPA, Spring FrameWork, Spring-Bacth, ApacheTomCat 6, Apache TomCat 7, Oracle SQL, GIT, JSON, SOAPUI, REST, MAVEN;

Customer: Bank - Bradesco

Responsible for organizing, maintaining, developing and automating systems banking interfaces in JSP, Servlets, javascript Java 5, Jsf 2.0, primefaces, Webservice, AWB 2, StarTeam, WinMerge, pdc-ejb-1.3,

myfaces-all-1.1.1, richfaces. Carrying out the creation of unit and integrated tests, preparation of documents for software, test scripting.

Java Developer / Analyst jr at BRQ IT Services - of 2014 until 2015.

Bank - Bradesco

Development and maintenance of IT solutions system for the financial market - using Java JEE, JSF, HTML, CSS, Javascript, Tomcat, communication with MainFrame, MyFaces, Tomahawk, Prime Faces, Systems integration with web services. Reports with JasperReport.

Analyst/Programmer Internship cobol / Java.

Responsible for organizing, maintaining, developing and automating banking systems. Analysis, specification, system design, programming, approval, implementation and monitoring of the systems requested by its users. Responsible for the optimization of various processes using the development of systems Cobol, Cobol Cics, Db2. Realization and creation of unit and integrated tests, elaboration of software documents, test scripting.